The greatest adventure is what lies ahead...
The Hobbit is a family, fantasy, animation film directed by Jules Bass.
The story follows the adventures of Bilbo Baggins, a diminutive creative who resides in a place called Middle-Earth
before he is compelled to go on a quest to find a treasure buried deep in the heart of the Lonely Mountain.
Bilbo Baggins (voice), played by Orson Bean.
Gandalf the Grey (voice), played by John Huston.
Thorin (voice), played by Hans Conried.
Smaug (voice), played by Richard Boone.
Gollum (voice), played by Theodore Gottlieb.
Elvenking (voice), played by Otto Preminger.
The Hobbit is a 1977 animated musical television special
created by Rankin/Bass and animated by Topcraft.
The film is an adaptation of the 1937 book of the same name by J.
Tolkien; it was first broadcast on NBC in the United
States on Sunday, November 27, 1977.
The teleplay won a Peabody Award; the film received a Christopher Award.
The New York Times found the film "curiously eclectic", but felt
that whatever its failings, it warranted attention.
The Tolkien scholar Douglas A.
Anderson called the adaptation "execrable"; the author Baird Searles called it an "abomination" and an attempt that had "failed
miserably", regretting the quality of the animation and of the soundtrack, and the omission of key plot points.
The film explores themes of gold, robbery, based on novel or book, elves, dwarf.
The tone is thought_provoking.